Guide to the Walter E. Fauntroy papers, 1941-1990 MS2070
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Congressional committee files, 1819-1989; MS2070 Series 4; 12 Linear feet
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brochure, "100th Congress: Members, Committee Assignments, and Staff Contacts", 1987-1988 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Fact Sheet, Senate Campaign Workers Assistance Project, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Article, "Congressional Record for 94th and 98th Congress", 1975-1983 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Clippings, Black Caucus Activities, 1971-1989 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Bicentennial Black Music Festival, 1976 March 11 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Title I Today: A Factbook, 1981 May 18 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, CBC Archives Project, 1981 June 11 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Black Leadership Form, 1981 June 24 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Solidarity Day, 1981 August 24 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, CBC 11th Legislative Weekend, 1981 October 02 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, National Black Youth Network, 1981 October 21 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, South Africa Loan, 1981 October 21-1982 October 19 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, People's Platform, 1984 April (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Assault on the MOVE House, 1985 May 20 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, CBC Foundation, 1989 June 29-August 09 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, David Cooke, 1989 September 21 (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Ronald Payne, 1989 October 13 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Ronald Thomas, 1989 October 16 (Box 54, Folder 22)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, Planned Parenthood, 1989 November 16 (Box 54, Folder 23)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, CBC Mandela Breakfast, 1990 June 11 (Box 54, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Correspondence, 20th Legislative Weekend, 1990 July 26 (Box 54, Folder 25)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Hearing Files, Racism in the Military, 1971 November 18 (Box 54, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Hearing Files, Harassment of Black Organizations, 1975 February 25 (Box 54, Folder 27)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Newsletter, Congressional Black Caucus Calls President's Budget "Disaster" for the American People, 1980 February 06 (Box 54, Folder 28)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Newsletter, Report to the People, Vol. 10- No. 1 & 2, Spring and Summer, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 29)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Newsletter, Point of View, 1982-1988 (Box 54, Folder 30)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Newsletter, This Week, 1983-1984 (Box 54, Folder 31)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Newsletter, Black Caucus Review, 1984 January (Box 54, Folder 32)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): News Releases, CBC Activities, 1976-1984 (Box 54, Folder 33)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): News Releases, Fauntroy Heads CBC, 1980 December 12 (Box 54, Folder 34)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): News Releases, Push/Coca Cola, 1981 August 25 (Box 54, Folder 35)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): News Releases, Loan to South Africa, 1982 October 18 (Box 54, Folder 36)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Plan, Congressional Black Caucus, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 37)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Plan, Ten Point Plan Toward a National Legislative Agenda, undated (Box 54, Folder 38)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Presentation, Congressional Black Caucus Workshop, 1982 September 17 (Box 54, Folder 39)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Proposal, Budget Alternatives (CBC & AFL-CIO), 1982 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Proposal, Budget Alternatives, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Resolution, Budget Alternatives, 1981 March 19 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Invitations, Chairman's Champagne Reception for CBC Staffers, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Program, Eleventh Annual Legislative Weekend, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Program, Thirteenth Annual Legislative Weekend, 1983 September 21-24 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Program, Eighteenth Annual Legislative Weekend, 1988 September (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Program, 19th Annual Legislative Weekend (preliminary), 1989 September (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Program. 19th Annual Legislative Weekend, 1989 September 13-17 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Remarks, CBC 19th Legislative Weekend, 1989 September 13 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Statements, Urban Law Institute, 1971 March 24 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Statements, Delivered by Members of CBC, 1971-1987 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Statement, CBC, Fiscal Year 1983 Budget and Economic Recovery Program (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Statement, Martin Luther King, Jr. Profile, undated (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Clippings, " A Black Voter Network", 1981 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Meeting Files, National Coalition on Black Voter Participation, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Meeting Files, CBC on Voter Participation, 1984 September 28 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: News Release, Congressional Hearing on Alabama Voter Fraud, 1985 June 13 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Pamphlet, NAACP Voter Education, undated (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Correspondence, CBC Youth Brain Trust and Summit, 1987 September 11 (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Flyer, Annual CBC Youth Brain Trust, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 21)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Meeting Files, Foreign Affairs Brain Trust Activities, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 22)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Program, Youth Brain Trust, 1985 September 27-1986 October 03 (Box 55, Folder 23)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): Brain Trust on Black Voter Participation: Statement, "Is African American Leadership Under Fire?", 1987 (Box 55, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): List, Founding Meeting Members, 1986 September 20 (Box 55, Folder 25)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): List, First Attendants to the Black Leadership Roundtable, 1986 October 11-1987 June 08 (Box 55, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Meeting Files, By-laws, Circa 1986 (Box 55, Folder 27)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Booklet, The Black Leadership Family Plan, 1982 February (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Booklet, The Peoples Platform, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Black Leadership Family Plan, 1982 March-April 11 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Lawrence Chimerine, 1984 February 05 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Clarence Mitchell, 1984 November 26 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Frank Henderson, 1985 February 19 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Alexis Roberson, 1985 March 06 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Black Leadership Roundtable Conference, 1985 April 12 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Lezli Baskerville, 1987 January 21-June 24 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Illiteracy Program, 1987 April 27 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Phillip Krajewski, 1987 December 01 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Wille Brown, 1988 March 11 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Correspondence, Clifford Alexander, 1988 March 14 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Meeting Files, Black Leadership Family Plan Conference Recommendations, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Meeting Files, NBLR Conference, 1985 March 15-17 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Meeting Files, NBLR Youth Leadership Institute, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Statement, Black Leadership Family Plan, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Statement, Round Up of Elections 1986 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Brochure, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Clippings, undated (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Flyer, Black Leadership Family Plan, undated (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Invitation, NBLR Avon Youth Awards, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Newsletter, The Roundtable Record, Vol. 1 No. 1, Summer 1985 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): News Release, Black History Month, undated (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Project, "Participate in `88, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Congressional Black Caucus (CBC): National Black Leadership Roundtable (NBLR): Summary, The Peoples Platform, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Caucus on Women: Newsletter, Update, 1983-March 31-September 30 (Box 56, Folder 27)
  - Congressional Caucus on Women: News Releases, Congressional Caucus on Women's Issues, 1983 February-November (Box 56, Folder 28)
- New Bethel Baptist Church files, 1959-1989; MS2070 Series 5; 1 Linear feet
  This series contains correspondence, articles, constitution, by-laws, booklets, reports, programs, news releases, remarks, statements, and souvenir books. These materials date from 1959-89. These records are documents from the New Bethel Baptist Church, where Fauntroy has served as pastor since 1959.
  - Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Blue Prints, New Bethel Baptist Church, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Booklet, "Giving Up To A Dream - Building Fund", 1986 November (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Booklet, "Steps to Christian Giving", undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, Weekly Church Bulletins, 1961 January-November (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Roster, Church Board of Trustees, Circa 1974 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Certificate, Membership to SCLC, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Certificate, Incomplete Dedication Certificate, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, New Bethel Baptist Church, 1968-1969 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Clipping, March on Washington, 1983 June 10 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Clipping, Fauntroy's 25th Anniversary as Pastor of New Bethel Baptist Church, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Clubs and Auxiliaries, 1959-1960 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Birmingham Movement, 1963 May 09 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Frank Johnston, 1972 May 09 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Henrietta Childs, 1972 July 27 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, S.S. Hodges, 1972 November 09 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Theodore Britton, 1973 January 10 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, John McCoy, 1973 April 25 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Music Department, 1974 May 22 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Walter Parish, 1974 July 30 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Vera Waddill, 1974 September 17 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Deacon Gaffney, 1974 November 09 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, re: Sale of Church Property, 1975 November 05 (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, John Meares, 1976 April 28 (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Nan Huhn, 1989 February 21 (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Community Services, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, R.R. Robinson, undated (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - Evaluations, Church Evaluation, 1959 July 02 (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - Meeting Files, Canvas Committee, 1964-1977 (Box 57, Folder 29)
  - Report, Financial Church Report, 1971-1974 (Box 57, Folder 30)
  - Plan, Church Layout, undated (Box 57, Folder 31)
  - Proposal, Church Funds, undated (Box 57, Folder 32)
  - Program, Installation Services, 1959 April 26-May 11 (Box 57, Folder 33)
  - Program, 2nd Anniversary as Pastor, 1961 May 14-22 (Box 57, Folder 34)
  - Program, 5th Anniversary as Pastor, 1964 May 10-18 (Box 57, Folder 35)
  - Program, 5th Anniversary as Pastor Reception, 1964 May 18 (Box 57, Folder 36)
  - Program, 6th Anniversary as Pastor Reception, 1965 May 17 (Box 57, Folder 37)
  - Program, 8th Anniversary as Pastor Reception, 1967 May 14-21 (Box 57, Folder 38)
  - Program, 10th Anniversary as Pastor, 1969 May 19 (Box 57, Folder 39)
  - Program, 12th Anniversary as Pastor, 1971 May 09-17 (Box 57, Folder 40)
  - Program, 14th Anniversary as Pastor, 1973 May 15 (Box 57, Folder 41)
  - Program, 24th Anniversary as Pastor, 1983 January 16 (Box 57, Folder 42)
  - Program, 25th Anniversary as Pastor, 1984 January 21-28 (Box 57, Folder 43)
  - Program, 26th Anniversary as Pastor, 1985 February 01-02 (Box 57, Folder 44)
  - Program, 75th Anniversary of Church, 1977 May 13-15 (Box 57, Folder 45)
  - Program, Virginia Union University, 1961 January 05 (Box 57, Folder 46)
  - Program, Mount Bethel Baptist Church, 1962 July 09 (Box 57, Folder 47)
  - Program, National Association of Negro Business & Professional Women's Clubs, Inc., 1963 May 04 (Box 57, Folder 48)
  - Program, Appreciation Service for Reverend Thomas Clifton Garnett, 1964 March 22 (Box 57, Folder 49)
  - Program, Zion Baptist Church, 1967 December 10 (Box 57, Folder 50)
  - Program, Choir No. II in Concert, 1968 May 26 (Box 57, Folder 51)
  - Program, Father of the Year, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 52)
  - Program, Man of the Year, 1969 June 15 (Box 57, Folder 53)
  - Program, 25th Anniversary of the Inspirational Chorus, 1969 October 12 (Box 57, Folder 54)
  - Program, Women's Day 1976 (Box 57, Folder 55)
  - Program, Funeral Service for William Diggs, 1977 March 26 (Box 57, Folder 56)
  - Program, D.C. Statehood Now, 1989 November 09 (Box 57, Folder 57)
  - News Releases, Conference on Urban Affairs, 1960 November 01 (Box 57, Folder 58)
  - News Releases, Urban Renewal Program, 1961 June 27 (Box 57, Folder 59)
  - News Releases, Debs and Masters for Christ Contest, 1983 April (Box 57, Folder 60)
  - News Releases, New England Baptist Missionary Convention, undated (Box 57, Folder 61)
  - Remarks, New Bethel Baptist Church Sponsored Discussion D.C. Statehood, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 62)
  - Statement, Bicentennial, Circa 1976 (Box 57, Folder 63)
  - Souvenir book, Centennial Souvenir Book, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 64)
- Oversize materials, 1963-1983; MS2070 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains photographs, banners, bumper stickers, flyers, and posters. This material dates from 1960-83. This material is related to various events such as community meetings, D.C. Statehood campaign, March on Washington, and civil rights protests.
  - Photograph, Community Meeting, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Photograph, Walter E. Fauntroy in Baseball Uniform [part of D.C. Statehood campaign], undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia: Bumper sticker, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia: Poster, "Support the Freedom-Loving People of Birmingham, Alabama", 1960-Circa 1963 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia: Flyer, "Culpeper County-Wide Civic Council", 1960-1968 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia: Banner, March on Washington, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia: Posters, Demonstration Posters for Civil and Student Rights, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Memorabilia: Shoes worn to March on Washington, 1963; Series 6 (Box 59)